humanity.com 2019-05-20

# Humanity - Privacy Policy

## Introductory provisions

Humanity® (“Humanity”, “we”, “us”, or “our”) treats everything related to personal data that is provided to us with respect and integrity. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website, as data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of our company. The use of our website is not possible without any indication of personal data.

The processing of personal data, such as, but not limited to, the name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number of a data subject will always be in line with the:

  * Australian Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988
  * General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), applicable in Europe;
  * Privacy Act U.S.C. 552a (Privacy Act of USA),
  * Privacy Acts in Latin America;
  * Any other country-specific data protection regulations applicable.

By means of this data protection declaration, our company would like to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal data we collect, use and process. Furthermore, data subjects are informed, by means of this data protection declaration, of the rights to which they are entitled.

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  1. What Personal Data we collect and why we collect it
  2. How we use Personal Data
  3. Who we share Personal Data with
  4. The choices we offer, including how to access, update, and remove Personal Data
  5. Handling human resources data transferred to us for processing on behalf of our customers; as well as human resources data of our employees.

Note: _Humanity.com, Inc. commits to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner, and comply with the advice given by the panel and/or Commissioner, with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and/or Switzerland, in the context of the employment relationship._

As controller and processor, we have implemented numerous technical and organizational measures to ensure the most complete protection of personal data processed through this website and application. However, internet-based data transmissions may, in principle, have security gaps occasionally, so absolute protection may not be guaranteed. For this reason, every data subject is free to transfer personal data to us via alternative means, e.g. by telephone.

Our website and application incorporate privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you will not receive direct marketing communications and will limit the publication of your information.

In your relationship with us through the website and application, controller, for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), other data protection laws applicable in Member states of the European Union and other provisions related to data protection, is:

Humanity Inc  
50 Osgood Place Suite 330 San Francisco, CA 94133

**This Policy applies to all Humanity® Websites, www.Humanity.com and our mobile application owned and operated by Humanity.com, Inc (Humanity). Our website includes links to other sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Humanity®.**

This Policy does not apply to other companies’ or organizations’ sites to which we link. You should carefully review the privacy policies of those sites in order to determine how they treat your personal information.

**If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and the applicable User Agreement, please exit, and do not access or use, the Service.**

We have kept this simple for your understanding, but if you’re not familiar with terms like “cookies” or “IP addresses,” feel free to contact us. Your privacy is really important to us, so whether you’re new to Humanity or a long-time user, please take the time to get to know our practices.

## Privacy Shield

The EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks were designed by the U.S. Department of Commerce, and the European Commission and Swiss Administration, respectively, to provide companies on both sides of the Atlantic with a mechanism to comply with data protection requirements when transferring personal data from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States in support of transatlantic commerce.

Humanity participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S Privacy Shield Framework. Humanity is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [[www.privacyshield.gov/list](http://www.privacyshield.gov/list)]

Humanity is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Humanity complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Humanity is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Humanity may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Humanity commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact Humanity at [info@humanity.com](mailto:info@humanity.com).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

## Use Cases

Please take a moment to understand which use case(s) set out in this Privacy Policy apply to you:

  * **Website Visitor**  
You are a “Website Visitor” by definition when you visit our website (www.humanity.com) and any subdomains associated with our principal domain (*.humanity.com).As a website visitor, we use your information for our own purposes. Primarily for improving the use of our website and to provide you with a more relevant browsing experience.
  * **Phone User**  
You are a “Phone User” by definition if you call any member of our team, including Sales, Client Success and Support for any purpose.
  * **Application User**  
You are an “Application User” if your organizations sign up to use the Humanity Service and you access the Humanity services through our applications, API’s, or through third-parties. If you are an application user, our primary purpose of using your personal data is for providing the Humanity Application services to you.
  * **Former Application User**  
You are a “Former Application User” if you leave the organization and cease access to the Humanity Application associated to your organization. We retain your personal information for a limited time and for limited purposes, such as to make it easier for you to re-join our service in the future or to wish you offers for services that we think you may be interested in.

## Definitions

Our data protection policy should be legible and understandable for the general public, as well as for our customers and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to first explain the terminology used.

In this data protection declaration, we use, inter alia, the following terms:

  * **Personal data**  
Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“data subject”). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
  * **Data subject**  
Data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person, whose personal data is processed by the controller responsible for the processing.
  * **Processing**  
Processing is any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.
  * **Restriction of processing**  
Restriction of processing is the marking of stored personal data with the aim of limiting their processing in the future.
  * **Profiling**  
Profiling means any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular to analyze or predict aspects concerning that natural person’s performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behavior, location or movements.
  * **Controller or controller responsible for the processing**  
Controller or controller responsible for the processing is the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data; where the purposes and means of such processing are determined by Union or Member State law, the controller or the specific criteria for its nomination may be provided for by Union or Member State law.
  * **Processor**  
Processor is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes personal data on behalf of the controller.
  * **Recipient**  
Recipient is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or another body, to which the personal data are disclosed, whether a third party or not. However, public authorities which may receive personal data in the framework of a particular inquiry in accordance with Union or Member State law shall not be regarded as recipients; the processing of those data by those public authorities shall be in compliance with the applicable data protection rules according to the purposes of the processing.
  * **Third party**  
Third party is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or body other than the data subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or processor, are authorized to process personal data.
  * **Consent**  
Consent of the data subject is any freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject’s wishes by which he or she, by a statement or by a clear affirmative action, signifies agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her.

## What Personal Data we collect and how do we collect it

All Personal Data that is collected through the use of the Humanity Application is stored in the United States of America.

Upon acquisition of our services, we will ask for your full name and a valid e-mail address, which will be included in our emailing list, for future updates, and eventual marketing promotions. In addition, at the end of the trial period, we will ask you to provide us with the secure payment data, which will be used for processing the order.

In this Section we have set out:

  * the general categories of personal data that we may process;
  * in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from our customers, the
  * source and specific categories of that data;
  * the purposes for which we may process personal data;
  * the legal bases of the processing.

We may process data about your use of our website and services ( **“usage data“** ). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, device type and operating system (e.g. versions), referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analyzing the use of the website and services.

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

We may process your account data ( **“account data“** ). The account data may include your name and email address. The account data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, updates, promotions, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services ( **“service data“** ). The service data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services ( **“enquiry data”** ). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information ( **“customer relationship data“** ). The customer relationship data may include your name, your employer, your job title or role, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you or your employer. The customer relationship data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our services ( **“transaction data“** ). The transaction data may include your contact details, and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ( **“correspondence data“** ). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.

**“Automatically Collected” Information** : The Humanity website collects a series of general data and information when a data subject or automated system calls up the website or application. This general data and information are stored in the server log files, and it is collected regardless of your quality: Website Visitor, Phone User, Application User or Former Application User.

Collected may be:

  * the ISP,
  * the operating system used by the accessing system
  * the website from which an accessing system reaches our website (so-called referrers)
  * the sub-website
  * the date and time of access to the website
  * an Internet Protocol address (IP address)
  * screen Resolution
  * locale Preferences
  * web page visited before you came to our website
  * information you search for on our website
  * date and time stamps associated with transactions
  * system configuration information and other interactions with the website.
  * call recordings – you will be notified whether the call is being recorded at the start of every call to us.
  * call log – including the phone number, time and date and length of call.
  * social networking information (if we are provided with access to your account on social network connection services);
  * any further personal data contained in any files that you upload, download, or create (“Files”) within the Humanity Application
  * any other similar data and information that may be used in the event of attacks on our information technology systems.

When using these general data and information, Humanity does not draw any conclusions about the data subject. Rather, this information is needed to:

  * deliver the content of our website correctly;
  * optimize the content of our website as well as its advertisement;
  * ensure the long-term viability of our information technology systems and website technology;
  * provide law enforcement authorities with the information necessary for criminal prosecution in case of a cyber-attack;

In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

Obviously, the access to our website for website visitors is free; however, we inform you that for the use of the website via mobile device the charges and the standard tariffs provided in the service contract that you have stipulated with them will still be applied by the telephone operators

### Former Application Users

If we retain your personal data once you have left your organization and cease to use your Humanity Account for our own purposes, we are a “data controller” for the purposes of the Data Protection Legislation.

Activities that we may carry out on this basis include:

  * Making announcements to you regarding our products and service offerings;
  * Providing you with any service offering outside of the Humanity Application directly;
  * Ensuring compliance with our own obligations under applicable law and regulations; and
  * Using your personal data to help us to establish, exercise or defend legal claims

### Privacy of minors

We do not collect or consciously request information from customers under the age of 18, nor do we consciously allow such customers to register with our services. Our services and their contents are not intended for children under the age of 18. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 18, we will delete this information as soon as possible.

If you believe we have any information about a child under the age of 18, please contact us.

## Use and Disclosure of personal data to others

We will use the received data to help you easily obtain assistance on your problems, after the acquisition of our services and application; to provide you with personalized content and information, including online listings or other forms of direct marketing; to offer, improve, test and monitor the effectiveness of our services; to develop and test new products and functions; to monitor metrics such as total visitor numbers, traffic and demographic models; to diagnose or solve technological problems; to automatically update the website and applications on your device.

We do not rent or sell your information to third parties outside of Humanity without your consent, unless otherwise provided on the basis of statutory provisions. We may share your information, as well as information from tools such as cookies or similar, with third party organizations that help us provide you with the services, but only as far as is reasonably necessary.

We may share your data as deemed appropriate and in accordance with applicable laws and conditions. This sharing of your personal data includes where we act as a data processor on behalf of your organization as per the instructions and obligations in the agreement between us and your organization. We may share your personal data in the following manner:

  * **Your Use:**  
Your personal data will be displayed on your profile page which may permit other individuals associated with your organization to access your personal information. If you use the community functions of the Humanity Application such as blogs, forums, wikis and messaging, you acknowledge and accept that your personal data shared via these services may be read, collected and used by Application Users with access to them. You must also be aware that any posts you make on the Humanity Application may remain despite the closing of your account.
  * **Third Parties:  
**We may, at our discretion, employ the services of third-party companies and individuals to supply, analyze and improve the Humanity Application. This includes, but is not limited to, data storage, database management, web analytics, maintenance support, payment processing and the upgrading or improving the Humanity Application. In providing services to us, these third parties may gain access to your personal data but will do so only in relation to undertaking tasks on our behalf under the agreement we hold with them. In such an event, your personal data is protected under stipulations similar to those in our Privacy Policy.
  * **Other Service Providers, Business Partners and Third Parties:  
**Your personal data may also be shared with agents or third-party service providers acting on behalf of Humanity. These third parties include but are not limited to professional advisers, telecommunication and internet service providers. Your personal information may be shared with these third parties where it is required for them to perform the services for which they have been contracted to undertake by Humanity; however, they are not permitted to use your personal data for any other purpose.
  * **Third-Party Applications:  
**With your consent, your personal data may be shared with third-party applications, for example when you access Humanity through one of these applications. Humanity is not responsible for how these third-party applications use your information. When accessing Humanity through a third-party application, it is solely your responsibility to ensure you trust the third-party application and that it as a privacy policy that protects your data in a way that you require.
  * **Legal Compliance and Law Enforcement:  
**We maintain the right to disclose files or data stored in your Humanity Application or Account and information we have collected about you through the use of our services when, in good faith, we believe doing so is reasonably required to comply with the law, regulatory requirements, enforced legal requests, or to protect Humanity’s intellectual property. In the event your data is provided to a law enforcement agency as per the above, Humanity will remove encryption from your files and data to enable access to law Enforcement.

**Transference of Your Data:**  
In the event that we are involved in a merger, acquisition or full or partial sale, your personal data may be transferred to associated parties as part of the transaction. Should this occur, you and/or you organization shall be notified to the change of ownership, control or use of your personal data, and if the transaction has made them subject to a different Privacy Policy. We will notification either via email, prominent notification on our website or through the Humanity Application.

**Group Companies:**  
We maintain the right to share your personal data with our group companies.

In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

We can access your information as well as store and share it in response to a request when the law requires us to do so. In addition, we may access your information, as well as store and share it, if we believe in good faith that this is necessary to: detect, prevent and manage fraud and other illegal activities; protect ourselves, you and other people, even in the context of any investigations; prevent events that could cause imminent physical damage or death.

We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

## Cookies and Tracking Technologies

Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which internet pages, servers or apps can be assigned to the specific app or server in which the cookie was stored.

Through the use of cookies or similar technologies, Humanity and its partners can provide the customers of this website and applications with more customer-friendly services that would not be possible without the cookie setting.

By means of a cookie, the information and offers on our website and applications can be optimized with the customer in mind. Cookies allow us, as previously mentioned, to recognize our website and applications customers. The purpose of this recognition is to make it easier for customers to utilize our website and applications. The website and applications customer that uses cookies, e.g. does not have to enter access data each time the website and applications is accessed, because this is taken over by the website and applications, and the cookie is thus stored on the customer’s computer system.

We may use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how you interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Service. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all aspects of the Application.

Some web browsers may transmit “do-no-track” signals to websites with which the browser communicates. Our website does not currently respond to these “do-not-track” signals.

**Strictly necessary cookies**

These cookies are essential, as they enable you to move around the Site and use its features, such as accessing secure areas. Without these cookies, some services you have asked for such as payment submission can’t be provided.

**Performance cookies**

These cookies collect information about how you use the Site, for example which pages you go to most often and if you get error messages from certain pages. These are used to improve how the Site works.

**Functionality cookies**

These cookies allow the Site to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you’re in). For instance, the Site uses functionality cookies to remember your language preference. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you’ve made to text size, font and other parts of pages that you can customize. They may also be used to provide services you’ve asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog.

**Targeting cookies**

These cookies are used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. They remember that you have visited a website and this information may be shared with other organizations such as advertisers. This means after you have been to the Site you may see some advertisements about our services elsewhere on the Internet.

The data subject may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website and application by means of a corresponding setting of the browser or app, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time. If the data subject deactivates the setting of cookies in the browser or app, then not all functions may be entirely usable.

We use automatically collected information and other information collected during the Services through cookies and similar technologies to:

  1. personalize our Service, such as remembering a Customer’s or Visitor’s information or login details so that the Customer or Visitor will not have to re-enter it during a visit or on subsequent accessing;
  2. provide customized content and information;
  3. monitor and analyze the effectiveness of website and applications and third-party activities;
  4. monitor site usage metrics such as the number of visitors.

**Mobile Analytics**

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

### Data Quality

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information we have about you is accurate, complete and up to date when we use it. Generally, we rely on you to assist us in keeping your personal information accurate and up to date.

### Data Security

We follow generally accepted standards and have taken reasonable steps to keep your personal information secure at all times and in accordance with our Information Security Policies. For example, electronic access is limited to authorized personnel.

We also take steps to reasonably protect your personal information from misuse and loss, unauthorized access, modification or disclosure and maintained in an accurate, complete and up-to-date manner. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us as set forth below in ‘How to Contact Us’.

### Openness

We will be honest and open with you about the type of personal information that we collect about you and the actual use of any such information. We will let you know at the time we collect your personal information, or soon after, how we will treat it.

If you require any details of the personal information held by us about you, then please contact us by phone or e-mail.

### Access, Correction and Deletion

We respect your privacy rights and provide you with reasonable access to the information we have collected about you and obtain a more in-depth explanation about how the information is used.

If you wish to access or amend any other personal information we hold about you, or to request that we delete any information about you that we have obtained through procuring our website and applications, you may contact us as set forth below in ‘How to Contact Us’. Unless personal information is required to be retained by us for administrative or legal reasons Humanity will meet such requests at the earliest possible opportunity.

If you would like access to detailed personal information and such information is not immediately or easily accessible by us, we may charge an administrative fee for our costs in retrieving and supplying the information to you.

### Opting out from Communications

If you receive emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the email or by sending an email to the address provided in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

Please be aware that if you opt-out of receiving emails from us or otherwise modify the nature or frequency of promotional communications you receive from us, it may take up to ten (10) business days for us to process your request. Please note that you may still receive administrative messages from us regarding our Services.

### Transfer of Data

We take reasonable steps to ensure that if any personal information you give us is transferred from one continent to another, that it will remain subject to the protection given by our privacy policy and undertaken in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the Australian Privacy Principles and USA Privacy Regulations where required.

## Data Controller and Data Processor

In accordance with the regulations provided by the:

  * Privacy Act U.S.C. 552a (Privacy Act of USA),
  * Privacy Acts in Latin America
  * the Privacy Act of 1988 of Australia  
the General Data Protection Regulation, aka GDPR for European Union  
the data controller and data processor for Humanity is the developer of the website and application.

Data Processor is also any third party that receives collected personal data from us.

### Sensitive Information

We do not believe in intrusive collection of your personal details and will not collect information that is considered highly personal or highly sensitive about you without your prior consent.

## Data Retention and Data Deletion

We only retain the personal information collected from a Customer for as long as the Customer’s email address is active on our mailing list, or otherwise for a limited period of time as long as we need it to fulfil the purposes for which we have initially collected it, unless otherwise required by law.

In some cases, it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on the 2-year criteria, after your relationship with us ends.

Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Article, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

### Your rights

Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under data protection law are:

  1. the right to access;
  2. the right to rectification;
  3. the right to erasure;
  4. the right to restrict processing;
  5. the right to object to processing;
  6. the right to data portability;
  7. the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
  8. the right to withdraw consent.

You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: [the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed]. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

  1. consent;
  2. that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,

and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.  
To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us.

### Complaints Resolution

We are committed to providing our clients with a fair and responsive system for handling and resolving complaints concerning the handling of their personal information. You have a right to complain and to have your complaint handled efficiently if you are concerned about our handling of your personal information. We believe that in receiving your complaint, we are provided with a valuable opportunity to improve the services we deliver to you and maintain your confidence in our services.

If at any time you wish to lodge a complaint in respect of the handling, use or disclosure of your personal information by us, you may do so by contacting us directly.

**We aim to investigate and advise you of the outcome of the complaint promptly.**

If you are not satisfied with our handling of your complaint, you may contact the Data Protection Officer at:  
+1 (866) 973-7866  
50 Osgood Place Suite 330 San Francisco, CA 94133

### Amendments

We may update this policy to reflect changes to our information practices. We encourage you to periodically review this page to ensure you have the latest information on our privacy practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email, or by means of a notice on this website, or through the private messaging system within our service system, prior to the change becoming effective.

## How to Contact Us

By letter:  
50 Osgood Place Suite 330 San Francisco, CA 94133

By email:  

By telephone:  
+1 (866) 973-7866
